Wow, what an honor. I always wondered what this would feel like.
يا له من شرف كبير. فلطالما تساءلت عمّا سيكون عليه هذا الشعور.
So eight years ago, I got the worst career advice of my life.
منذ ثماني سنوات، تلقّيت أسوأ نصيحة مهنية في حياتي.
I had a friend tell me,
فقد قال لي أحد أصدقائي:
"Don't worry about how much you like the work you're doing now.
"لا تلقِ بالًا لكونك تحب عملك الذي تقوم به أم لا.
It's all about just building your resume."
فكل ما يهم هو بناء سيرتك الذاتية."
And I'd just come back from living in Spain for a while,
كنت قد عدت للتوّ من إسبانيا حيث كنت أعيش،
and I'd joined this Fortune 500 company. I thought, "This is fantastic.
وانضممت لشركة مدرجة في قائمة "فورتشن 500" وقلت لنفسي: هذا رائع!
I'm going to have big impact on the world."
سوف أحدث تأثيرًا عظيمًا على العالم.
I had all these ideas. And within about two months,
راودتني كل تلك الأفكار. ولكن في غضون شهرين،
I noticed at about 10am every morning I had this strange urge
بدأت ألاحظ أنني عند العاشرة صباحًا من كل يوم تنتابني رغبة غريبة
to want to slam my head through the monitor of my computer.
بأن أضرب رأسي بشاشة الحاسوب.
I don't know if anyone's ever felt that.
لا أدري إن شعر أحدكم بالمثل من قبل.
And I noticed pretty soon after that that all the competitors in our space
وما لبثت أن لاحظت أن جميع الشركات المنافسة في مجال عملنا،
had already automated my job role.
قد أحلت الآلة في العمل الذي أقوم به.
And this is right about when I got this sage advice to build up my resume.
وتزامن ذلك مع تلك النصيحة العظيمة بشأن بناء سيرتي الذاتية.
Well, as I'm trying to figure out
وفي أثناء محاولتي لاكتشاف
what two-story window I'm going to jump out of and change things up,
التغيير الجذري الذي يتوجب علي القيام به لأتخلص من ذلك الوضع،
I read some altogether different advice from Warren Buffett, and he said,
قرأت نصيحة مختلفة كليًّا من وارن بافيت، حيث قال:
"Taking jobs to build up your resume is the same as saving up sex for old age."
"قيامك بعمل ما من أجل بناء سيرتك الذاتية يشبه تأجيل ممارسة الجنس لحين الهرم"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I heard that, and that was all I needed.
وقد أخذت بنصيحته تلك، وكان ذلك كل ما أحتاجه.
Within two weeks, I was out of there, and I left with one intention:
ففي أسبوعين، غادرت تلك الشركة وفي ذهني أمر واحد:
to find something that I could screw up. That's how tough it was.
أن أجد شيئًا يمكنني إفساده. كان الأمر بتلك الصعوبة.
I wanted to have some type of impact. It didn't matter what it was.
أردت أن أحدث أثرًا ما، مهما يكن ذلك الأثر.
And I found pretty quickly that I wasn't alone:
وسرعان ما اكتشفت أنني لست الوحيد:
it turns out that over 80 percent of the people around
فقد وجدت أن أكثر من 80% من الناس
don't enjoy their work.
لا يستمتعون بالقيام بعملهم.
I'm guessing this room is different,
أظن أن الأمر مختلف هنا،
but that's the average that Deloitte has done with their studies.
ولكن ذلك هو المعدل الذي خلصت إليه دراسات ديلويت.
So I wanted to find out, what is it that sets these people apart,
وهكذا، أردت معرفة ما يميز أولئك الأشخاص.
the people who do the passionate, world-changing work,
أولئك الشغوفين الذين يحدثون تغييرًا في العالم.
that wake up inspired every day,
ويستيقظون كل صباح يملؤهم الإلهام
and then these people, the other 80 percent
وكذلك الأخرين و هم نسبة 80%
who lead these lives of quiet desperation.
من الذين يعيشون بصمت حياة كاملة من اليأس.
So I started to interview all these people doing this inspiring work,
وهكذا، أجريت مقابلات مع أولئك الذين يقومون بأعمال ملهمة،
and I read books and did case studies,
وقرأت الكتب واطلعت على الحالات والأمثلة.
300 books altogether on purpose and career and all this,
300 كتاب حول المسيرة المهنية وغايات الحياة وإلى ما هنالك.
totally just self-immersion, really for the selfish reason of --
وأغرقت نفسي تمامًا، وذلك لهدف شخصي خاص،
I wanted to find the work that I couldn't not do,
فقد أردت أن أعرف ما هي المهنة المثالية بالنسبة لي،
what that was for me.
ما الذي خلقت لأجله!
But as I was doing this, more and more people started to ask me,
ولكن خلال ذلك، بدأ المزيد من الناس يسألونني:
"You're into this career thing.
"أنت مهتم بمجال العمل والمهنة؛
I don't like my job. Can we sit down for lunch?"
أنا لا أحب عملي، هل يمكن أن نتحدث؟"
I'd say, "Sure." But I would have to warn them,
فأقول: "بالتأكيد". لكنني كنت أحذرهم.
because at this point, my quit rate was also 80 percent.
ففي تلك المرحلة، بلغت نسبة ترك العمل 80% أيضًا.
Of the people I'd sit down with for lunch, 80 percent would quit their job
كان 80% ممن أجلس للتحدث معهم يتركون عملهم،
within two months.
في غضون شهرين.
I was proud of this, and it wasn't that I had any special magic.
كنت فخورً بذلك، ولم يكن الأمر يتعلق بسحرٍ ما خاص بي.
It was that I would ask one simple question.
فقد كنت أوجه سؤالًا بسيطًا واحدًا:
It was, "Why are you doing the work that you're doing?"
"لمَ تقوم بالعمل الذي تقوم به؟"
And so often their answer would be,
وغالبًا ما كان جوابهم:
"Well, because somebody told me I'm supposed to."
"لأن أحدًا ما قال لي إن عليّ فعل ذلك"
And I realized that so many people around us
وأدركت أن الكثيرين حولنا،
are climbing their way up this ladder that someone tells them to climb,
يصعدون على ذلك السلّم الذي قال لهم الآخرون أن يصعدوه،
and it ends up being leaned up against the wrong wall,
لينتهي بهم الأمر وهم يستندون على الجدار الخاطئ،
or no wall at all.
أو أنهم لا يجدون جدارًا أصلًا.
The more time I spent around these people and saw this problem,
وكلما أمضيت وقتًا مع هؤلاء الأشخاص ولمست هذه المشكلة،
I thought, what if we could create a community,
قلت لنفسي، لمَ لا ننشئ مجتمعًا،
a place where people could feel like they belonged
مكانًا يشعر فيه الناس بالانتماء،
and that it was OK to do things differently,
وأن بإمكانهم أن يكونوا مختلفين،
to take the road less traveled, where that was encouraged,
وأن يسلكوا سبلًا غير مألوفة، ويحفزوا الآخرين
and inspire people to change?
على التغيير!
And that later became what I now call Live Your Legend,
وذلك ما بتُّ أسميه: "عش أسطورتك".
which I'll explain in a little bit.
وسأتحدث عن ذلك بعد قليل.
But as I've made these discoveries, I noticed a framework
ولكن في أثناء ذلك، لاحظت وجود إطار
of really three simple things
مؤلف من ثلاثة أشياء بسيطة،
that all these different passionate world-changers have in common,
يتقاسمه كل أولئك الأشخاص الشغوفين بتغيير العالم.
whether you're a Steve Jobs or if you're just, you know,
سواء كنت ستيف جوبس، أو كنت ذلك الشخص
the person that has the bakery down the street.
صاحب محل المعجنات عند ناصية الشارع.
But you're doing work that embodies who you are.
المهم أنك تقوم بالعمل الذي يجسد حقيقتك.
I want to share those three with you, so we can use them as a lens
أود أن أخبرك بتلك الأشياء الثلاثة، والتي ستكون بمثابة العدسة
for the rest of today and hopefully the rest of our life.
لبقية هذا اليوم، وربما لبقية حياتنا.
The first part of this three-step passionate work framework
الجزء الأول من إطار العمل المكون من ثلاث خطوات،
is becoming a self-expert and understanding yourself,
هو أن تصبح "خبيرًا بذاتك" وأن تفهم نفسك.
because if you don't know what you're looking for,
لأنك إن لم تدرك ما تبحث عنه،
you're never going to find it.
فإنك لن تجده أبدًا.
And the thing is that no one is going to do this for us.
وذلك أمر لن يفعله أحدٌ لنا.
There's no major in university on passion and purpose and career.
فليس ثمة تخصص جامعي في الشغف أو الغاية أو الهدف.
I don't know how that's not a required double major,
ولا أفهم كيف لا يمثل ذلك تخصصًا مطلوبًا من الكل.
but don't even get me started on that.
لكنني لم أبدأ قصتي بعد.
I mean, you spend more time picking out a dorm room TV set
فأنت تمضي وقتًا أطول في اختيار جهاز تلفزيون لغرفة نومك،
than you do you picking your major and your area of study.
من الوقت الذي تمضيه في تحديد تخصصك أو مجال دراستك.
But the point is, it's on us to figure that out,
ولكن نحن من يجب أن يقرر ذلك،
and we need a framework, we need a way to navigate through this.
لذا فإننا بحاجة لإطار محدد، وسبيل يمكننا من خلاله استكشاف ذلك.
And so the first step of our compass is finding out what our unique strengths are.
وتتمثل الخطوة الأولى في مسيرتنا في تحديد نقاط قوتنا المميزة.
What are the things that we wake up loving to do no matter what,
ما هي الأشياء التي نرغب بفعلها مهما كلف الأمر؛
whether we're paid or we're not paid, the things that people thank us for?
سواء تلقينا أجرًا لقاء ذلك أم لا، الأشياء التي يشكرنا الآخرون عليها.
And the Strengths Finder 2.0 is a book and also an online tool.
Strengths Finder 2.0 هو كتاب وأداة عبر الإنترنت أيضًا،
I highly recommend it for sorting out what it is that you're naturally good at.
وأنصح باستخدامها بشدة لاكتشاف مواهبك ومهاراتك الطبيعية.
And next, what's our framework or our hierarchy for making decisions?
ما الخطوة التالية في إطار عملية اتخاذ القرار؟
Do we care about the people, our family, health,
هل نهتم بالآخرين؟ بالعائلة؟ بالصحة؟
or is it achievement, success, all this stuff?
أم بالإنجاز، والنجاح، وإلى ما هنالك؟
We have to figure out what it is to make these decisions,
يتوجب علينا الإجابة على ذلك بغية اتخاذ القرار الصائب.
so we know what our soul is made of,
ولنعرف مما جُبلت روحنا بالضبط،
so that we don't go selling it to some cause we don't give a shit about.
لكي لا نبيعها من أجل قضية لا تعنينا مطلقًا.
And then the next step is our experiences.
الخطوة التالية هي تجاربنا.
All of us have these experiences. We learn things every day, every minute
فجميعنا لدينا تجارب. ونتعلم منها كل يوم وكل دقيقة؛
about what we love, what we hate,
عما نحب ونكره؛
what we're good at, what we're terrible at.
عما نجيد وفيمَا نفشل؛
And if we don't spend time paying attention to that
وإذا لم ننفق الوقت الكافي بالتفكير بذلك،
and assimilating that learning
واستيعاب الدروس منه،
and applying it to the rest of our lives, it's all for nothing.
وتطبيقه على بقية حياتنا، فإن ذلك سيضيع هباءً.
Every day, every week, every month of every year
ففي كل يوم وكل أسبوع، و في كل شهر من كل سنة،
I spend some time just reflecting on what went right,
أمضي بعض الوقت في التفكير بما مر بي
what went wrong, and what do I want to repeat,
من أمور جيدة وسيئة، وما الذي أود فعله من جديد؛
what can I apply more to my life.
ما الذي يمكنني تطبيقه في حياتي.
And even more so than that, as you see people, especially today,
علاوة على ذلك، عندما ترى أشخاصًا، وخاصةً اليوم،
who inspire you, who are doing things where you say
ممن يلهمونك، إذ يقومون بأشياء تجعلك تقول:
"Oh God, what Jeff is doing, I want to be like him."
"يا إلهي، يا له من عمل يقوم به جيف، أريد أن أكون مثله"
Why are you saying that? Open up a journal.
لمَ تقول ذلك؟ افتح دفترك،
Write down what it is about them that inspires you.
وسجل صفاتهم التي تلهمك.
It's not going to be everything about their life,
لن يكون ذلك كل تفاصيل حياتهم؛
but whatever it is, take note on that,
ولكن مهما يكن ذلك، سجله ضمن ملاحظاتك.
so over time we'll have this repository of things
وبمرور الوقت، سيتكون لديك مخزون من الأشياء
that we can use to apply to our life and have a more passionate existence
يمكنك استخدامه وتطبيقه في حياتك لتصبح أكثر أهمية وشغفًا،
and make a better impact.
وتحدث أثرًا أكبر.
Because when we start to put these things together,
ذلك أننا عندما نجمع تلك الأشياء معًا،
we can then define what success actually means to us,
فإننا نستطيع تحديد المعنى الحقيقي للنجاح بالنسبة لنا.
and without these different parts of the compass, it's impossible.
ويغدو الأمر مستحيلًا من دون تلك الأجزاء المختلفة من البوصلة،
We end up in the situation -- we have that scripted life
حيث ينتهي بنا الأمر بأن نعيش حياة مخططة مسبقًا؛
that everybody seems to be living going up this ladder to nowhere.
حيث يصعد الجميع على ذلك السلم الذي لا يقود إلى أي مكان.
It's kind of like in Wall Street 2, if anybody saw that,
الأمر يشبه فيلم "وول ستريت 2"، هل شاهده أحد منكم؟
the peon employee asks the big Wall Street banker CEO,
حيث يسأل الموظف الكادح المدير والشخصية الهامة في وول ستريت:
"What's your number? Everyone's got a number,
"كم يبلغ رقمك؟ فكل شخص لديه رقم،
where if they make this money, they'll leave it all."
بحيث إذا استطاع جمع ذلك المبلغ، فسيترك الأمر برمته"
He says, "Oh, it's simple. More."
فيجيب المدير: "حسنٌ، الجواب بسيط: المزيد."
And he just smiles.
ثم يبتسم ببساطة.
And it's the sad state of most of the people
تلك هي الحالة المحزنة لمعظم الناس،
that haven't spent time understanding what matters for them,
الذين لم يمضوا الوقت الكافي لاستكشاف ما يهمهم بالفعل،
who keep reaching for something that doesn't mean anything to us,
والذين يسعون باستمرار للحصول على أشياء لا تعنيهم مطلقًا،
but we're doing it because everyone said we're supposed to.
لكنهم يفعلونها لأن الآخرين يقولون إن عليهم فعل ذلك.
But once we have this framework together,
ولكن بمجرد أن نضع ذلك الإطار،
we can start to identify the things that make us come alive.
يمكننا تحديد الأشياء التي تحيينا من الداخل.
You know, before this, a passion could come and hit you in the face,
كما تعلم، يمكن لشغف ما أن يفاجئك بغتةً،
or maybe in your possible line of work, you might throw it away
وربما تصدفه أثناء عملك، ولا تلقي إليه بالًا،
because you don't have a way of identifying it.
لأنك لا تملك وسيلة لتحديده.
But once you do, you can see something that's congruent with my strengths,
ولكن بمجرد أن تفعل، فإنك ستحصل على شيء ينسجم مع نقاط قوتك،
my values, who I am as a person,
وقيمك، وحقيقتك كإنسان.
so I'm going to grab ahold of this, I'm going to do something with it,
وهكذا، يمكنك أن تتشبث به، وأن تفعل شيئًا به،
and I'm going to pursue it and try to make an impact with it.
و أن تتابعه وتحدث أثرًا من خلاله،
And Live Your Legend and the movement we've built
و"تعيش أسطورتك". ولم يكن لهذه الحركة التي بدأناها
wouldn't exist if I didn't have this compass to identify,
أن تتحقق لو لم يكن لدي تلك البوصلة،
"Wow, this is something I want to pursue and make a difference with."
"ذلك أمر أود متابعته وإحداث فرق من خلاله".
If we don't know what we're looking for, we're never going to find it,
إذا لم أعرف ما الذي أبحث عنه، فإنني لن أجده أبدًا،
but once we have this framework, this compass,
ولكن بمجرد أن نوجد هذا الإطار، هذه البوصلة،
then we can move on to what's next -- and that's not me up there --
فإن بإمكاننا الانتقال إلى الخطوة التالية. وليس الأمر أنني أفعل المستحيل
doing the impossible and pushing our limits.
وأدفع الحدود قدمًا.
There's two reasons why people don't do things.
هناك سببان يمنعان الناس من القيام بفعل ما.
One is they tell themselves they can't do them,
إما أنهم يقولون إنهم لا يستطيعون فعله،
or people around them tell them they can't do them.
أو أن من حولهم يقولون لهم ذلك.
Either way, we start to believe it.
في كلتي الحالتين، نحن نصدق ذلك.
Either we give up, or we never start in the first place.
فإما أن نستسلم، أو أننا لا نبدأ أصلًا.
The things is, everything was impossible until somebody did it.
في الواقع، كل شيء كان مستحيلًا إلى أن قام به أحد ما.
Every invention, every new thing in the world,
كل اختراع، كل شيء جديد في العالم،
people thought were crazy at first.
كان الناس يظنونه جنونًا في البداية.
Roger Bannister and the four-minute mile, it was a physical impossibility
قطع روجر بانستر مسافة ميل في أقل من أربع دقائق. كان من المستحيل
to break the four-minute mile in a foot race
كسر حاجز الأربع دقائق في سباق على الأقدام،
until Roger Bannister stood up and did it.
إلى أن تجرأ روجر بانستر وفعلها.
And then what happened?
ما الذي حدث بعد ذلك؟
Two months later, 16 people broke the four-minute mile.
بعد شهرين، نجح 16 شخصًا في كسر ذلك الحاجز.
The things that we have in our head that we think are impossible
إن ما نعتقد في أذهاننا أنه مستحيل
are often just milestones waiting to be accomplished
هو في الواقع إنجاز ينتظر من يحققه،
if we can push those limits a bit.
إن استطعنا توسيع حدودنا قليلًا.
And I think this starts with probably your physical body and fitness
ويبدأ ذلك من جسدك وقدراتك البدنية
more than anything, because we can control that.
قبل أي شيء آخر. ذلك أن بإمكاننا التحكم بها.
If you don't think you can run a mile,
إذا ظننت أنك لا تستطيع الجري لميل،
you show yourself you can run a mile or two,
أثبت لنفسك أن بإمكانك قطع ميل أو اثنين،
or a marathon, or lose five pounds, or whatever it is,
أو خوض ماراتون، أو إنقاص بضعة كيلوغرامات،
you realize that confidence compounds
وستدرك أن الثقة تتراكم،
and can be transferred into the rest of your world.
وتنتقل لبقية نواحي حياتك.
And I've actually gotten into the habit of this a little bit with my friends.
لقد اعتدت هذه العادة مع أصدقائي:
We have this little group. We go on physical adventures,
لدينا مجموعة صغيرة، ونذهب معًا في مغامرات رياضية.
and recently, I found myself in a kind of precarious spot.
وقد وجدت نفسي مؤخرًا في مكان محفوف بالمخاطر،
I'm terrified of deep, dark, blue water.
حيث كنت أرتعد خوفًا من المياه الزرقاء العميقة.
I don't know if anyone's ever had that same fear
لا أعلم إن كان أحدكم قد اختبر ذلك الخوف.
ever since they watched Jaws 1, 2, 3 and 4 like six times
بعد مشاهدتي لفيلم Jaws بأجزائه الأربعة نحو 6 مرات،
when I was a kid.
عندما كنت طفلًا.
But anything above here, if it's murky, I can already feel it right now.
ولكن أي شيء يتجاوز هذا الارتفاع، إذا كان موحلًا،فإنني أذكر الإحساس تمامًا،
I swear there's something in there.
أقسم أن شيئًا ما كان هناك.
Even if it's Lake Tahoe, it's fresh water, totally unfounded fear,
حتى إن كنت في بحيرة تاهو، حيث المياه عذبة ثمة خوف غير مبرر.
ridiculous, but it's there.
أمر سخيف، لكنه موجود.
Anyway, three years ago I find myself on this tugboat
منذ ثلاث سنوات، وجدت نفسي على متن قارب
right down here in the San Francisco Bay.
هنا في خليج سان فرانسيسكو.
It's a rainy, stormy, windy day, and people are getting sick on the boat,
كان يومًا ماطرًا عاصفًا، والناس على متن القارب يشعرون بالغثيان،
and I'm sitting there wearing a wetsuit, and I'm looking out the window
وأنا أجلس هناك أرتدي بزة الغطس وأنظر من النافذة،
in pure terror thinking I'm about to swim to my death.
يملؤني الرعب وأنا أفكر بأنني سأموت غرقًا.
I'm going to try to swim across the Golden Gate.
سوف أحاول السباحة عبر جولد جيت،
And my guess is some people in this room might have done that before.
وأعتقد أن بعض من في القاعة قد جربوا القيام بذلك بالفعل.
I'm sitting there, and my buddy Jonathan, who had talked me into it,
كنت أجلس هناك، إلى جانب صديقي جوناثان، الذي أقنعني بالذهاب إلى هناك.
he comes up to me and he could see the state I was in.
نظر إلي ولاحظ ما كنت أعانيه،
And he says, "Scott, hey man, what's the worst that could happen?
وقال: "سكوت، ما هو أسوأ ما قد يحدث؟
You're wearing a wetsuit. You're not going to sink.
أنت ترتدي بزة غطس، ولن تغرق؛
And If you can't make it, just hop on one of the 20 kayaks.
وإذا لم تستطع السباحة، اقفز إلى أحد قوارب النجاة العشرين؛
Plus, if there's a shark attack, why are they going to pick you
وإذا هجمت أسماك القرش، فلمَ ستختارك أنت
over the 80 people in the water?" So thanks, that helps.
من بين أكثر من 80 شخصًا في الماء؟" شكرًا لك، ذلك مريح
He's like, "But really, just have fun with this. Good luck."
وأضاف: "استمتع بوقتك، حظًا سعيدًا"
And he dives in, swims off. OK.
ثم غطس في الماء، وتابع السباحة.
Turns out, the pep talk totally worked, and I felt this total feeling of calm,
اكتشفت أن تلك المحادثة القصيرة قد آتت أُكلها، وغمرني شعور بالهدوء.
and I think it was because Jonathan was 13 years old.
أعتقد أن ذلك يعود إلى أن جوناثان كان في الثالثة عشرة من عمره.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And of the 80 people swimming that day,
ومن بين 80 شخصًا كانوا يسبحون ذلك اليوم،
65 of them were between the ages of nine and 13.
كان 65 منهم بين التاسعة والـ13 من العمر.
Think how you would have approached your world differently
فكر كيف كنت ستنظر إلى العالم بشكل مختلف،
if at nine years old you found out you could swim a mile and a half
لو أنك اكتشفت في سن التاسعة أن بإمكانك السباحة لميل ونصف،
in 56-degree water from Alcatraz to San Francisco.
في مياه درجة حرارتها 13 من ألكاتراز إلى سان فرانسيسكو.
What would you have said yes to?
ما الذي كنت ستوافق عليه؟
What would you have not given up on? What would you have tried?
ما الذي لم تكن لتتخلى عنه؟ ما الذي كنت ستجربه؟
As I'm finishing this swim, I get to Aquatic Park,
عندما انتهيت من السباحة وصلت إلى أكواتك بارك،
and I'm getting out of the water
وخرجت من المياه.
and of course half the kids are already finished,
بالطبع كان نصف الأولاد قد وصلوا أيضاً،
so they're cheering me on and they're all excited.
وكانوا يشجعونني بحماس.
And I got total popsicle head, if anyone's ever swam in the Bay,
كنت أتجمد من البرد، كما تعلمون،
and I'm trying to just thaw my face out, and I'm watching people finish.
وكنت أحاول أن أدفئ وجهي، وأنا أراقب الناس يقتربون من خط النهاية،
And I see this one kid, something didn't look right.
ورأيت أحد الأولاد، لم يكن على ما يرام.
And he's just flailing like this.
كان يتخبط هكذا،
And he's barely able to sip some air before he slams his head back down.
وكان بالكاد يستطيع التنفس قبل أن يعود برأسه تحت الماء؛
And I notice other parents were watching too,
ولاحظت وجود بعض الأهالي الذين يتابعون المشهد،
and I swear they were thinking the same thing I was:
وأقسم أنهم كانوا يفكرون مثلي:
this is why you don't let nine-year-olds swim from Alcatraz.
هذا ما يمنعك من السماح لطفل في التاسعة من السباحة من ألكاتراز.
This was not fatigue.
لم يكن ذلك مجرد تعب.
All of a sudden, two parents run up and grab him,
فجأةً، هب اثنان من الأهالي والتقطاه،
and they put him on their shoulders, and they're dragging him like this,
ووضعاه على كتفيهما ومشيا به هكذا.
totally limp.
كانا يعرجان؛
And then all of a sudden they walk a few more feet
ثم مشيا بضع خطوات أخرى،
and they plop him down in his wheelchair.
ووضعاه في كرسي مدولب،
And he puts his fists up in the most insane show of victory I've ever seen.
ليرفع قبضتيه عاليًا في إشارة مذهلة للنصر، لم أرها من قبل.
I can still feel the warmth and the energy on this guy
أستطيع تحسس الدفء والطاقة التي كان يشع بها ذلك الطفل
when he made this accomplishment.
عندما حقق إنجازه.
I had seen him earlier that day in his wheelchair.
كنت قد رأيته في وقت سابق من ذلك اليوم على كرسيه المدولب،
I just had no idea he was going to swim.
لكني لم أدرك أنه كان سيسبح.
I mean, where is he going to be in 20 years?
ما الذي سيكون عليه عندما يصبح في العشرين؟
How many people told him he couldn't do that, that he would die if he tried that?
كم من الأشخاص قالوا له إنه لن يتمكن من ذلك وإنه سيموت إن فعل؟
You prove people wrong, you prove yourself wrong,
أنت تثبت للآخرين ولنفسك أنهم على خطأ،
that you can make little incremental pushes
وأن بإمكانك تحقيق خطوات صغيرة متتالية،
of what you believe is possible.
نحو ما تعتقد أنه ممكن.
You don't have to be the fastest marathoner in the world,
ليس عليك أن تكون أسرع عدّاء في العالم.
just your own impossibilities, to accomplish those,
فكر بما يمكنك تحقيقه،
and it starts with little bitty steps.
وابدأ تلك الخطوات الصغيرة.
And the best way to do this
وأفضل طريقة لفعل ذلك،
is to surround yourself with passionate people.
هي أن تحيط نفسك بأشخاص متفانين شغوفين.
The fastest things to do things you don't think can be done
أسرع طريقة لتقوم بأشياء لا تظنها ممكنة،
is to surround yourself with people already doing them.
هي أن تحيط نفسك بأشخاص يقومون بها بالفعل.
There's this quote by Jim Rohn and it says.
ثمة مقولة لجيم رون تقول:
"You are the average of the five people you spend the most time with."
"الإنسان هو متوسط مجموع الأشخاص الخمسة الذي يقضي معهم أكثر وقته"
And there is no bigger lifehack in the history of the world
ليس هناك عائق في التاريخ البشري
from getting where you are today to where you want to be
أمام الانتقال من حيث أنت إلى حيث تودّ أن تكون،
than the people you choose to put in your corner.
أهم من الأشخاص الذين تختار وجودهم في حياتك؛
They change everything, and it's a proven fact.
فهم يستطيعون تغيير كل شيء، تلك حقيقة مثبتة.
In 1898, Norman Triplett did this study with a bunch of cyclists,
في عام 1898، أجرى نورمان تريبلت تجربة على مجموعة من الدرّاجين،
and he would measure their times around the track in a group,
حيث قام بحساب زمن دورانهم حول الحلبة ضمن مجموعة،
and also individually.
وبشكل انفرادي أيضًا.
And he found that every time the cyclists in the group would cycle faster.
وخلص إلى أن الدراجين يقطعون الحلبة بسرعة أكبرعندما يكونون ضمن مجموعة.
And it's been repeated in all kinds of walks of life since then,
وتكررت التجربة عبر جميع نواحي الحياة منذ ذلك الوقت،
and it proves the same thing over again,
وثبتت صحتها مرة تلو أخرى:
that the people around you matter, and environment is everything.
أن الأشخاص حولك لهم تأثير كبير، وأن البيئة هي كل شيء؛
But it's on you to control it, because it can go both ways.
ولكن عليك التحكم بها، لأنها قد تدفعك باتجاهين متعاكسين.
With 80 percent of people who don't like the work they do,
ففي حالة الـ80% الذين لا يحبون عملهم،
that means most people around us, not in this room, but everywhere else,
وذلك يعني النسبة الأكبر من الناس، ليس في هذه الغرفة، بل في كل مكان،
are encouraging complacency and keeping us from pursuing the things that matter to us
يدفعوننا نحو التراخي ويمنعوننا من تحقيق ما نصبو إليه؛
so we have to manage those surroundings.
لذا فإن علينا التعامل جيدًا مع محيطنا.
I found myself in this situation --
وقد وجدت نفسي في تلك الحالة.
personal example, a couple years ago.
ومثال شخصي على ذلك، منذ بضع سنوات.
Has anyone ever had a hobby or a passion they poured their heart and soul into,
هل سبق لأحدكم أن كانت لديه هواية أو شغف شغل قلبه وروحه،
unbelievable amount of time, and they so badly want to call it a business,
وقضى معظم وقته فيه، وأراد بشدة أن يكون ذلك عمله ومهنته،
but no one's paying attention and it doesn't make a dime?
لكن أحدًا لم يلقِ بالًا له، ولم يكسب منه قرشًا واحدًا؟
OK, I was there for four years trying to build this Live Your Legend movement
حسنًا، لقد مررت بذلك حيث قضيت أربع سنوات في محاولة بناء حركة "عش أسطورتك"
to help people do work that they genuinely cared about and that inspired them,
لمساعدة الأشخاص على ممارسة العمل الذي يلهمهم ويحبونه بالفعل،
and I was doing all I could,
كنت أبذل قصارى جهدي،
and there were only three people paying attention,
وكان ثلاثة أشخاص فقط يهتمون بما أقول،
and they're all right there: my mother, father and my wife, Chelsea.
وهم معنا هنا اليوم: أمي، وأبي، وزوجتي تشلسي.
Thank you guys for the support.
شكرًا لكم أعزائي على دعمكم لي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق).
And this is how badly I wanted it, it grew at zero percent for four years,
كنت أرغب بذلك بشدة، لكني لم أحقق أي نمو خلال أربع سنوات،
and I was about to shut it down,
وكنت على وشك التوقف عن العمل،
and right about then,
وفي ذلك الوقت بالذات،
I moved to San Francisco and started to meet some pretty interesting people
انتقلت إلى سان فرانسيسكو وبدأت ألتقي ببعض الأشخاص المميزين،
who had these crazy lifestyles of adventure,
الذين يعيشون حياة مليئة بالإثارة والمغامرة،
of businesses and websites and blogs
وأعمال ومواقع ومدونات،
that surrounded their passions and helped people in a meaningful way.
أحاطت بشغفهم وساعدتهم بصورة إيجابية.
And one of my friends, now, he has a family of eight,
أحد أصدقائي، وقد بات لديه عائلة من 8 أشخاص،
and he supports his whole family
يتولى مسؤوليتهم جميعًا،
with a blog that he writes for twice a week.
من خلال مدونة يكتب فيها مرتين أسبوعيًا.
They just came back from a month in Europe, all of them together.
لقد رجعوا جميعًا للتو من رحلة إلى أوروبا استمرت شهرًا.
This blew my mind. How does this even exist?
أثار ذلك الأمر دهشتي. كيف يمكن ذلك؟
And I got unbelievably inspired by seeing this,
وقد ألهمني ذلك إلى حد بعيد،
and instead of shutting it down, I decided, let's take it seriously.
وبدلًا من التوقف عن العمل، قررت أن أعمل بجدية أكبر.
And I did everything I could to spend my time,
وبذلت قصارى جهدي لأمضي كل ساعة
every waking hour possible trying to hound these guys,
من وقتي في محاولة لتقصّي أولئك الأشخاص،
hanging out and having beers and workouts, whatever it was.
نخرج معًا، ونحتسي الجعة، ونمارس الرياضة، وغير ذلك.
And after four years of zero growth,
وبعد أربع سنوات من عدم النمو،
within six months of hanging around these people,
وفي غضون ستة أشهر من رفقة أولئك الأشخاص،
the community at Live Your Legend grew by 10 times.
تنامى مجتمع "عش أسطورتك" بمقدار عشرة أضعاف.
In another 12 months, it grew by 160 times.
وفي الأشهر الاثني عشر التالية، تنامى بمقدار 160 ضعفًا.
And today over 30,000 people from 158 countries
واليوم، يستخدم أكثر من 30 ألف شخص من 158 دولة
use our career and connection tools on a monthly basis.
أدوات التواصل المهني التي نقدمها بصورة شهرية.
And those people have made up that community of passionate folks
وبات هؤلاء يشكلون مجتمعًا من الأفراد الشغوفين،
who inspired that possibility that I dreamed of
الذين ألهموني إمكانية تحقيق ما حلمت به،
for Live Your Legend so many years back.
في "عش أسطورتك" لعدة سنوات مضت.
The people change everything, and this is why --
الناس يغيرون كل شيء، وإليكم السبب.
you know, you ask what was going on.
حسنًا، أنتم تتساءلون عمّ حدث.
Well, for four years, I knew nobody in this space,
لأربع سنوات خلت، لم أكن أعرف أحدًا في هذا المجال،
and I didn't even know it existed, that people could do this stuff,
ولم أكن أعي وجوده أصلًا، وأن بإمكان أحد أن يقوم بهذا،
that you could have movements like this.
وأن أتمكن من إطلاق هذه الحركة.
And then I'm over here in San Francisco, and everyone around me was doing it.
ثم أتيت إلى سان فرانسيسكو، وكان كل من حولي يقوم بذلك.
It became normal, so my thinking went from how could I possibly do this
أصبح الأمر عاديًا، وهكذا تحوّل تفكيري من "كيف يمكنني فعل ذلك"،
to how could I possibly not.
إلى "كيف يمكنني ألا أفعل ذلك"!
And right then, when that happens, that switch goes on in your head,
وعندها بالضبط، يحدث ذلك التحول لديك،
it ripples across your whole world.
ويغيّر عالمك برمته.
And without even trying, your standards go from here to here.
ودون أن تشعر، تتحول معاييرك من هنا، إلى هنا.
You don't need to change your goals. You just need to change your surroundings.
لست بحاجة لتغيير أهدافك. عليك فقط تغيير محيطك.
That's it, and that's why I love being around this whole group of people,
هذا كل ما في الأمر، ولذا فإنني أحب أن أبقى برفقة هؤلاء الأشخاص،
why I go to every TED event I can,
وأن أحضر فعاليات TED كلما استطعت،
and watch them on my iPad on the way to work, whatever it is.
وأن أشاهدها عبر الآيباد في طريقي إلى العمل.
Because this is the group of people that inspires possibility.
فهؤلاء هم من يلهمون الممكن.
We have a whole day to spend together and plenty more.
لدينا اليوم بطوله معًا، وغير ذلك الكثير.
To sum things up, in terms of these three pillars,
لنلخص الأمر إذًا، من حيث تلك الركائز الثلاث،
they all have one thing in common more than anything else.
إذ أن شيئًا واحدًا يجمعها معًا.
They are 100 percent in our control.
وهو أنها ضمن نطاق تحكمنا بالكامل.
No one can tell you you can't learn about yourself.
فلا أحد يستطيع منعك من معرفة ذاتك.
you can't push your limits
أو من توسيع نطاق حدودك،
and learn your own impossible and push that.
ومعرفة ما هو مستحيل بالنسبة لك، ثم تغيير ذلك.
No one can tell you you can't surround yourself with inspiring people
لا أحد يستطيع منعك من إحاطة نفسك بأشخاص ملهمين،
or get away from the people who bring you down.
أو الابتعاد عن الأشخاص المحبطين.
You can't control a recession.
لا يمكنك التحكم بحدوث كساد.
You can't control getting fired or getting in a car accident.
أو بأن تطرد من عملك، أو أن يقع معك حادث سير.
Most things are totally out of our hands.
فمعظم الأشياء خارجة عن إرادتنا.
These three things are totally on us,
أما هذه الأشياء الثلاثة، فهي تتعلق بنا بالكامل.
and they can change our whole world if we decide to do something about it.
ويمكنها أن تغير عالمنا برمّته لو أردنا فعل شيء حيال ذلك.
And the thing is, it's starting to happen on a widespread level.
والمثير في الأمر، أن ذلك بدأ ينتشر على صعيد واسع النطاق.
I just read in Forbes, the US Government reported for the first time
فقد قرأت في "فوربس" أن الحكومة الأمريكية قد صرحت للمرة الأولى
in a month where more people had quit their jobs
أن عدد المستقيلين من وظائفهم قد تجاوز عدد
than had been laid off.
الذين تم تسريحهم خلال شهر.
They thought this was an anomaly, but it's happened three months straight.
واعتقدوا أن تلك كانت حالة شاذة، لكن الأمر تكرر لثلاثة شهور متتالية.
In a time where people claim it's kind of a tough environment,
وفي وقت يعتقد فيه الناس أننا نمر بأوقات عصيبة،
people are giving a middle finger to this scripted life,
يدير آخرون ظهورهم لهذا النمط المعلّب من الحياة،
the things that people say you're supposed to do,
حيث يخبرك الآخرون بما يجب عليك فعله،
in exchange for things that matter to them and do the things that inspire them.
بدلًا من القيام بما تحب، وفعل ما يلهمك.
And the thing is, people are waking up to this possibility,
والمثير أن الناس بدأوا يتنبّهون إلى هذه الإمكانية،
that really the only thing that limits possibility now is imagination.
وأن ما يحدّ من المكانات اليوم هو المخيّلة.
That's not a cliché anymore.
لم تعد هذه جملة مبتذلة.
I don't care what it is that you're into, what passion, what hobby.
لا يهمني ما الذي تحب القيام به، أو ما هي هوايتك.
If you're into knitting, you can find someone who is killing it knitting,
فإن كنت تحب الحياكة، فستجد من يبرع فيها ويهواها،
and you can learn from them. It's wild.
ويمكنك تتبّعه والتعلم منه. أنت حر.
And that's what this whole day is about, to learn from the folks speaking,
وذلك هو ما يدور هنا اليوم، أن نتعلم من المتحدثين،
and we profile these people on Live Your Legend every day,
ونحن نعرض لهؤلاء الأشخاص في "عش أسطورتك" كل يوم،
because when ordinary people are doing the extraordinary,
لأنه عندما يقوم أشخاص اعتياديون بأفعال غير اعتيادية،
and we can be around that,
ويمكنا لنا الاحتكاك بهم،
it becomes normal.
فإن ذلك يصبح عاديًا.
And this isn't about being Gandhi or Steve Jobs, doing something crazy.
ليس عليك أن تكون "غاندي" أو "ستيف جوبس"، أو أن تقوم بعمل خارق.
It's just about doing something that matters to you,
كل ما عليك هو القيام بأمر يهمك فعلًا،
and makes an impact that only you can make.
وأن تحدث أثرًا لا أحد غيرك يمكنه فعله.
Speaking of Gandhi, he was a recovering lawyer,
وبمناسبة الحديث عن غاندي، فقد كان محامي تعويضات،
as I've heard the term,
ذلك هو المصطلح كما سمعته،
and he was called to a greater cause, something that mattered to him,
وقد تبنّى قضيةً أسمى، أمرًا كان يعنيه حقًا،
he couldn't not do.
ولم يكن يستطيع ألا يفعله.
And he has this quote that I absolutely live by.
اشتهر غاندي بمقولة أؤمن بها تمامًا.
"First they ignore you, then they laugh at you,
و هي "يتجاهلونك في البداية، ثم يسخرون منك ،
then they fight you, then you win."
ثم يحاربونك، فتنتصر."
Everything was impossible until somebody did it.
كل شيء كان مستحيلًا، إلى أن قام أحد ما بفعله.
You can either hang around the people who tell you it can't be done
يمكنك إما أن تبقى بقرب أشخاص يقولون إن ذلك مستحيل،
and tell you you're stupid for trying,
ويخبرونك بأن من الغباء محاولة ذلك،
or surround yourself with the people who inspire possibility,
أو أن تحيط نفسك بأشخاص يلهمونك ما هو ممكن،
the people who are in this room.
كالأشخاص الموجودين في هذه القاعة.
Because I see it as our responsibility to show the world
فأنا أرى أن من مسؤولياتنا أن نُظهر للعالم
that what's seen as impossible can become that new normal.
أن ما يبدو مستحيلًا قد يصبح عاديًا.
And that's already starting to happen.
وقد بدأ ذلك يحدث بالفعل.
First, do the things that inspire us,
أولًا، افعل ما يلهمك،
so we can inspire other people to do the things that inspire them.
بحيث تستطيع إلهام الآخرين فعل ما يلهمهم.
But we can't find that
لكننا لن نستطيع العثور على ذلك
unless we know what we're looking for.
ما لم نعلم ما الذي نبحث عنه أولًا.
We have to do our work on ourself,
علينا القيام بعملنا بأنفسنا،
be intentional about that, and make those discoveries.
احزم أمرك بشأن ذلك، وقم بتلك الاستكشافات.
Because I imagine a world where 80 percent of people love the work they do.
إذ أنني أتخيل عالمًا يحب فيه 80% من الناس العمل الذي يمارسونه.
What would that look like?
كيف سيبدو ذلك العالم؟
What would the innovation be like? How would you treat the people around you?
كم سيحوي من الابتكار؟ كيف ستعامل الناس المحيطين بك؟
Things would start to change.
سوف يبدأ التغيير.
And as we finish up, I have just one question to ask you guys,
وختامًا، لدي سؤال واحد أتوجه به إليكم،
and I think it's the only question that matters.
وأعتقد أنه السؤال الوحيد المهم.
And it's what is the work you can't not do?
"ما هو العمل الذي لا يمكنك ألا تقوم به؟"
Discover that, live it,
اكتشف ذلك، وعشه،
not just for you, but for everybody around you,
ليس من أجلك فحسب، بل من أجل كل من حولك أيضًا،
because that is what starts to change the world.
لأن ذلك هو ما سيغيّر العالم.
What is the work you can't not do?
ما هو العمل الذي لا يمكنك ألا تقوم به؟
Thank you guys.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)